Jean-Paul Pando

UI/UX, Interactive Design + Development

Washington, DC - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Jean-Paul-Pando/3a1b0efc6547dc00

10+ years of experience creating interactive websites, application interfaces and mobile design solutions. Expertise in Front End design and development, including Javascript/JQuery, banners and infographics. Highly versed presenter, brander and digital illustrator for national and local clientele.

Additional background includes filming/video editing, and the creation of motion graphics. Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

UX Designer

FINRA - Rockville, MD - September 2015 to Present

Performed UX redesigns and feature addition to several internal applications. Interfaces focussed on timekeeping, time entry, bulk approvals/rejections, and logical use of icons.

Web Designer

Fannie Mae - Washington, DC - March 2014 to September 2015

Performed scripting and design for FANNIE MAE QUARTERLY, Digital Publication distributed company-wide. Created advertisements for THE HOME STORY, satellite page launched in early 2015.

Web Designer/Developer

HP Enterprise Services - Washington, DC - February 2011 to September 2013

Design, development, and requirements gathering for ICE.gov and ICE Intranet. Projects included the design, re-design and implementation of interactive tools for SEVIS and other ICE affiliates, and JS code optimization.

Completed iTunes 'Operation: Predator' phone app in cooperation with Office of Public Affairs (OPA).

Sr. Designer

Department of Justice - Washington, DC - March 2010 to December 2010

Responsibilities

Performed the redesign, coding and implementation of the Civil Rights Department (CRT) of the DOJ. Sketched and rendered wireframes to optimize display of multiple content sources. Designed and publishednew interactive menus using JQuery and cross browser-compliant CSS, IE 6+.

Accomplishments

Introduced new interactive elements to Justice.gov/crt, successfully lobbied for updates to the CRT styleguide, also customized and populated the satellite website servicemembers.gov

Skills Used HTML CSS JQuery wireframing

requirements gathering

EDUCATION

B.S in Studio Art

James Madison University 2002

M.S in Digital Design

Philadelphia University - Philadelphia, PA

SKILLS

Web Design, Graphic Design, Front End Development, JQuery, Adobe Creative Suite, branding, interface design

LINKS

http://www.jp-pando.com